azleg.gov 2006-12-08

# Privacy Statement

**Privacy Statement**

This website is designed as a public service and as such we do not collect any personal data without your knowledge.

If you only browse the website during your visit and input no data, we collect no personal information about you. As you visit our web site software automatically collects and stores only the following information about your visit, mostly for statistical purposes.

> · The name of the domain and IP address from which you access our website.  
>  · The type of browser used to access our site  
>  · The date and time you access our site  
>  · The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site  
>  · The pages you visit  
>  · Sections of the website you attempted to visit but were unable to due to programming or other technical problems.

Software programs are used to create summary statistics from this information for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, or provide any personal information using an on-line form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse this Web site and read or download any information provided on the site.

The site does use Internet cookies, however, session variables (e.g. an active connection between a user and the website) are used to keep track of information about your visit to the website. For example, it tracks what Legislative session you're currently working with. The cookies are temporary and will expire upon closing your browser or due to inactivity.

If the user volunteers personal information, the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information may be considered public record, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

In the State of Arizona, laws exist to ensure that government is open, and the public has a right to access most records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs, including the privacy of individuals. Both state and federal laws provide exceptions.

The Arizona Legislative Computer Services is the developer and manager of this Web site and has taken steps to safeguard the integrity of its data, and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained. 

Our site includes links to other websites that are not included under this privacy policy.

* * *
